The programme you 're about to watch
is a unique live investigation of the supernatural .
It contains material which
some viewers may find to be disturbing .
No creaking gates ,
no Gothic towers , no shutter windows ,
yet , for the past 10 months ,
this house has been the focus of an astonishing barrage
of supernatural activity .
This footage was shot by parapsychologists investigating the case .
Now , you 're about to see one of the incidents
that have earned this house its reputation .
- Let 's see what you think . - I can 't sleep . Turn the light off .
Mum said if you don 't ...
All right . All right .
( BANGING )
Mum .
Mum . Mum ! Mummy ,
it 's back ! It 's back !
- Mum ! - Mum .
Mum . Mum .
- Help me . - ( SCREAMING )
- Help me . - Don 't touch me !
- ( HIT ON THE DOOR ) - Don 't touch me .
( SCREAMING )
- Don 't .. - ( BOTH SCREAM )
- Quickly ! - Mum ! Mum !
- Mum . - Mum .
( SCREAMING )
( THEME MUSIC PLAYING )
MICHAEL : So welcome live this Halloween night
to the first ever TV Ghostwatch .
That 's the scene in Foxhill Drive in Northolt .
They are outside broadcasting this
and there , that 's the house
where it might all happen tonight
or it might not . We shall see .
We 're going to investigate one of the most baffling
and fascinating areas of human experience ,
the supernatural .
Tonight , television is going ghost-hunting
in an unprecedented scientific experiment , where we hope to show you
for the first time irrefutable proof that
ghosts really do exist .
I 'm joined in the studio by Dr Lin Pascoe
to give her expert technical advice .
Throughout the programme , I 'll be taking other expert opinion
about the supernatural from both here and America .
You 'll be telling us your ghost stories .
And as our tale unfolds , we 'll be taking your calls
about just what you 're seeing .
Well , let 's go to the main location of our programme ,
the house in Foxhill Drive .
Craig Charles , a well-known ghost hunter ,
is our reporter .
Craig , how are you ?
Hi , Michael .
Yeah , I 'm fine .
I 've taken the Valium , man .
Later on , we 're gonna be interviewing
the medium who tried unsuccessfully
to exorcise the house behind me .
I wonder if he 's heard from Elvis lately .
All right , there . With me is Pam Early , the mum of the house .
- Hello , Pam . - Hello .
And she 's gonna be taking us through the whole spine-tingling story .
( HUMMING THE TWILIGHT ZONE THEME )
And after that , you can share with us your own supernatural experience
on our very own Halloween witch-board .
I mean , switchboard .
- Over to you Smithy . - MIKE : Thanks , Craig .
We 'll come back to you later on .
All right , this part of the studio
is your part of the studio
this evening , because this is the phone number
we 'd like you to call us on .
You can now see our Ghostwatch team are here
ready to take your calls .
We particularly want to hear from you
if you 've had any personal experiences
of ghosts or the supernatural . Call us now .
As a matter of fact , of course , Mike Smith
has a very particular reason
for keeping a beady eye on the proceedings tonight .
- Michael . - Well , so would you , if your wife had just told you
she was gonna spend the best part of her night
in the most haunted house in Britain .
Of course we 're taking about Sarah Greene .
And Sarah is our reporter who 'll be spending the night ,
actually , inside our haunted house .
She was very keen to do it , I understand , Mike .
Oh , yeah , jumped at the chance .
Actually , so did I , because
we 've both been interested in ghosts and that weird sort of stuff .
And to be honest , I could never have
sat at home tonight on my own and watched this programme .
I 'm safer here .
MICHAEL : All right , Mike , thanks a lot .
Now , confrontations , of course , with the supernatural ,
can be devastatingly real .
Let 's find out what effect they 've had
on Mrs Early and her family .
So , how destructive has the haunting actually been ?
Mum kept on blaming us for breaking stuff .
We weren 't doing anything .
I 've lost track , really , I have .
Plates , teapots , cups , a broken tap ,
we got this thick smell , so disgusting , from the tap .
And stains got on clothes from nowhere , out of thin air .
- And in the central heating vent . - The man came , and ...
He couldn 't understand it , he said it was impossible .
Everybody said it was impossible .
I said , " Great . You come and live with ' impossible ' . "
So many things have happened ...
You start thinking ...
I don 't know ...
Maybe you 've done something wrong .
It 's wrecked my ... My house ,
my home , my family ...
CRAIG : It 's okay .
Over to you , Michael .
Dr Lin Pascoe , it 's a disturbing interview , that , isn 't it ?
You investigated the Northolt poltergeist for eight months , wasn 't it ?
What can be done for people like Mrs Early ?
According to the evidence on that film , clearly she 's shattered .
Well , the first thing we can all do for a start is
believe them .
Well , it 's not always that easy , is it ?
Yes , but you can see ,
it 's obvious these people are desperate for help .
Makes me so angry when you still get people out there
denying that these things even happen .
All right , Dr Pascoe , for the moment , thank you very much indeed .
Lin Pascoe will be giving her expert commentary
right throughout the programme .
And by the way , for those night owls amongst you ,
we 'll be here with updates roughly every hour ,
right through the night .
Well , now it 's high time we met our intrepid ghost-watcher ,
Sarah Greene .
First hospital watch , Sarah , now a ghost watch , big difference .
Well , I suppose the truth is I love a mystery ,
and who knows , we may get to the bottom of this one .
Actually , my own experience with things ghostly ,
albeit very brief , was so intriguing ,
I thought I might get the chance to learn a bit more tonight .
Well , perhaps , we might get a chance
to hear more of your story later on .
Yeah , if we get an opportunity , I 'd love to .
Actually , Smithy was there when I had my encounter
with what I think was a ghost .
- But he wasn 't quite as struck as me , there , were you ... - Well , no . Well , yes .
I mean , I think , this is the right environment so study these things .
Yeah , that 's why I get sent out here to the frontline
and you stay all cosy and safe and sound in the studio , isn 't it ?
Well , good luck , and I 'll see you later .
Now , before we go into the lion 's den ,
I 'd like to introduce you to Alan Demescu .
He is an electronics engineer ,
and a member of the Society for Psychical Research .
Now , Alan , we have a whole array
of technology here with us .
What are you hoping to discover tonight ?
Well , the paranormal covers a wide range of aspects ,
but tonight , we 're concentrating on
what we call , " Spontaneous cases . "
What are they exactly ?
Well , anything from inexplicable noises ,
footsteps , knocking ,
irrefutive voices , presences , the feeling of being watched ,
er , electrical interference ,
say , you know , your TV , lights , telephone ...
Right along at the far end of the spectrum
to actual , full-blown visual apparitions .
Now , we 've got our own BBC scanner here
but what are you using it for exactly ?
Well , we 've got a remote video camera
mounted in every room .
Erm ...
We have our image analysis equipment linked in ,
the tape is timecoded .
And atmospheric condition and temperature
are logged onscreen by sensors .
Those are like the little burglar alarms
- with the red lights . - Right .
Except , they 're triggered by cold
instead of heat .
Erm , intense cold spots are a secondary phenomenon .
We also want to detect low and high frequencies .
Basically , any aberration at all
could be a signal or a clue .
Well , we hope you get lots of both of those .
- We 'll leave you to it , Alan . - Okay .
And , we 'll go back outside
where I 'm going to be able to introduce you to
two of the very important people
who are at the frontline of this vigil ,
as psychical researchers call it .
Now , the first person is actually standing right behind the camera ,
and if he hands over to me , you 'll notice two things .
First of all ,
that his hand is a lot steadier than mine ,
and secondly , that he bears
a remarkable resemblance to Mike Gatting .
Yes , you do . ( LAUGHS )
- Chris Miller . - Hi .
SARAH : Now , Chris , does this camera differ in any way
from the sort of camera you 'd normally use on an outside broadcast ?
Well , it 's a normal lightweight mobile camera ,
but in this case , it 's been adapted
so we can use infrared as well .
- SARAH : Can we see how that works , Chris ... - Yeah , sure .
... if I hand this back to you ?
SARAH : What 's the best way to demonstrate it ?
CHRIS : Well , if we can kill the lights ...
SARAH : Okay , Clive , can we pop the lights down now ?
CHRIS : There you go . SARAH : Wow . How 's that ?
- CHRIS : I can see you quite clearly now . - Oh , look .
Yeah , so can I , on a monitor .
I 'm quite close to you though .
I mean , what about the people down here ?
If we move down here ... How fast can you move
with that thing on your shoulder , actually ?
- Quite fast . - It 's not bad .
Who needs a Steadicam when you got Chris Miller ?
That 's what I say .
Oh , yes , there they are .
CHRIS : There they all are .
( SARAH LAUGHING )
CHRIS : Somebody wants to get in the frame .
SARAH : Funny , they can see what they look like .
I 'll tell you what though , this means for us , doesn 't it ,
that nothing can lurk in the shadows .
CHRIS : That 's right , there 's no hiding place .
Absolutely .
Erm , right , let 's have the lights back up again then .
Okay , now , we 've got our vision back .
I think it 's time to meet sound .
Man of sound mind here , Mike Aiton .
Not only can this gentleman hear
an ant scratching its back legs at 50 yards ,
he 's also the unofficial chairman
of the Adrian Edmonson Lookalike Society .
Right on .
SARAH : So , if you 're not scared of ghosts ,
you 're scared of that .
How are you feeling about tonight ?
Are you a bit nervous at all ?
We will see .
Erm , how about you , Chris ?
I 'm okay .
- Are you ready to go in then ? - Yeah .
Okay . Well , we 'll see you later .
And ... ( CHUCKLES )
( ALL CLAPPING )
It 's time to go once more into the breach .
- Do I have to go first ? - CHRIS : After you .
Yeah , typical . Come on then , chaps .
Hello ?
Here we are .
Hi , Pam . Now , oh , look here we are .
This is the burglar alarm that
Alan Demescu was talking about .
Can we make ourselves at home ?
Kim , Suzanne .
Can I join you for a bit of apple bobbing , do you think ?
Well , we 'll let Sarah and her jolly team
settle down there for the night .
I wonder if they 'll remain as jolly as that
all evening . We shall find out .
Er , Dr Pascoe , let me ask you ,
why did you first of all ...
Why did you choose that particular house ?
Well , it was a decision we made over many weeks really .
What happened is that
we ran a computer programme
of all the haunted locations in the UK ,
and then we did a census of all the various investigators ,
and they were all unanimous that
Foxhill had more tangible phenomena on record than ...
I was gonna say any place in the world ,
but certainly any place in the UK .
We 'll see evidence of that , of course , later on in the programme .
What 's the chance , do you think , of us seeing anything tonight ?
I don 't honestly know .
Sometimes we saw nothing for weeks ,
and then , other times things were coming through
thick and fast , I mean , so much so that
we had difficulty logging it all .
I mean , some nights it was like , er ...
( EXHALES ) Being in a circus or a war zone or something .
- " A war zone " ? - It was that bad .
What about Halloween ?
Will that make any difference , do you think ?
Yeah , I think it will .
Certainly , there were more reports on Halloween
than almost any other night of the year .
But maybe that 's because people expect to see things .
- I 'm taking out no bets . I 'm hopeful . - ( CHUCKLES )
All right . Yes , we 're all hopeful .
Let 's take a phone call .
Mike Smith , what you got for us ?
This is Emma Stableford , and she 's from Slough .
Thank you . Emma ? Emma , hello .
- EMMA : ( ON PHONE ) Hello ? - Yeah .
EMMA : ( ON PHONE ) I did have a story ,
but there 's actually something else I 'd like to say to Dr Pascoe .
- MICHAEL : Go on . - EMMA : ( ON PHONE ) But I feel a bit foolish .
Oh , don 't worry about that , Emma .
Never worries me .
EMMA : ( ON PHONE ) Well , you know , at the beginning
when you showed the real footage of that haunted bedroom ?
Well , I know it was dark ,
but I was sure I could see a figure standing behind
against the wall , just by the curtain .
Very , very faint , but definitely a figure there .
A woman .
A person 's body , at least .
Standing there in a black dress .
Emma , I 've examined that particular piece of film
many times and so I 'm not sure ...
MICHAEL : I 'll tell you what to do , Emma ,
if you can actually spot up
the specific point on that tape
where you saw this figure ...
Tell one of our operators ,
we 'll actually spool it back to the point where you tell us ,
and then I 'll get Dr Pascoe here
to have a good look at it . Okay ?
- Great . - EMMA : ( ON PHONE ) Yeah .
All right . Thanks for calling .
Before you go , Emma ,
could you give a full description of what you thought you saw
to somebody manning the phones please ? Can you do that ?
- EMMA : ( ON PHONE ) Yeah , I will . - Great .
- MICHAEL : Okay , Emma , thanks a lot . - Thank you .
- Bye-bye . Bye-bye . - EMMA : ( ON PHONE ) Bye .
I tell you what we 'll do .
While we search for that piece of tape ,
let 's find out what Sarah 's up to .
MIKE : Sarah , did you hear that ?
Somebody thinks they 've seen a presence in the house .
- Today ? - MIKE : You 've not noticed anything this evening ,
- have you ? - No , nothing to report from here yet ,
except how absolutely useless I am at apple-bobbing .
Come on , girls . Yes , you 've done it , I can see .
( KNOCKING )
- Who 's that ? - ( KNOCKING )
Can you hear that ?
Can you hear this ?
Are you hearing ...
( KNOCKING )
It 's coming from in ...
- ( GROWLING ) - ( SCREAMING )
You ...
( ALL LAUGHING )
You are a complete and utter beast .
" Beast " ? I got it ! Look at that . It 's worse than Mike Smith , isn 't it ?
I don 't know though .
Is it your idea , this , Smithy ? You set this up ?
Well , I had a bet with your husband ,
I could get a four-letter-word uttered on television ,
I nearly did , as well . It was " beast " . B-E-A-S-T . Beast .
You 're a class act .
I think that is such a cheap shot , I have to say .
I mean , you know , I can take a joke with the best of them ,
but we 're all holed up in here ...
Well , I 'm sorry if I 'm being insensitive , but it is my brief .
They said , " Craig , come along , be insensitive . "
Can you just get out of the way a minute ?
- You 're in the middle of my close-up . - Oh , with pleasure .
They were in on it . They were in on it .
- Give me an apple . Give me an apple . - You were ?
Sorry , chaps , I love you all ,
if there 's any ghosts , keep them to yourselves .
- SARAH : Love us and leave us , go on . - I love you .
You needn 't smirk , Mike Smith , you were in on this .
I think you 're in a certain amount of trouble
with her indoors for that little situation .
I 'm sorry there , Doctor . Our producer , in fact , created a happening in the house
just in case we were on a wild ghost hunt , so to speak .
- DR PASCOE : We aren 't , I promise you . - All right .
Well , let 's go back to Sarah now .
Sarah , when you 're ready let 's hear the real story ,
the strange happenings at Foxhill Drive .
And by the way , have you got over your shock yet ?
Yes , I have recovered now , thank you , Michael .
Let me fill you in on what 's been happening here so far .
Let 's face it , there 's violence
at some time or another in every part of London ,
and this estate is no exception .
But there are some days , and certainly nights
when Mrs Early and her two daughters
would rather be out on the street
than right here , within their own four walls .
Let 's go upstairs for a moment .
It all began in here on December the 28th , 1991 .
Who was the first person to experience something ?
Suzanne .
We had a bit of an argument
because Suzanne wanted to stay up and watch some film and I wouldn 't let her .
- Go on , Suze , you say what happened . - No , you say .
She went to bed about ,
- Erm ... - I was in bed .
Mum came in to tuck me in ,
instead she just stood by the bed , looking at me .
At least I thought it was her .
And then she just turned and went .
The thing is , I didn 't tuck them in that night .
I always do ,
but that night I fell asleep in front of the television .
I told her she must have been dreaming .
Then a few days later , it was my room .
SARAH : Should we go and have a look ?
A few days later ,
these terrible noises woke me coming from the walls
like a bat , like a thudding .
All around you ?
Yes , like the whole room was going to come apart .
Did anybody else hear it ?
Yes , Suzanne and Kim heard it .
Kimmy , if you heard it too ,
what sort of a noise was it ?
( HITTING THE FLOOR )
We were screaming , I was shouting ,
" What is it ? What is it ? "
Well , I didn 't know what to say , they were that terrified .
So , I said it was pipes .
You know , the central heating .
So , afterwards , whenever Kim heard something
she 'd say , " It 's Pipes . Pipes is here . "
SARAH : So by this time , Kim , you could actually feel something as well , could you ?
Whereabouts was it coming from ?
There .
SARAH : What is it that 's over there ?
Pipes , that 's where he hides .
SARAH : Does he live there ?
Where does he live then ? Anywhere ?
On the stairs .
SARAH : Kim , how do you know he lives down there ?
Because I saw him through the crack .
He was there . He was staring at me .
SARAH : What happened after you saw him ?
I drew a picture of him .
- SARAH : Have you kept it ? - Yeah .
- SARAH : Can we have a look ? - Yeah .
Let 's have a look .
Was that exactly how he looked when you saw him ?
KIM : Yeah , he was disgusting .
Really disgusting .
It 's a good picture . Yeah .
No . ( WHISPERING ) Keep it . It 's a present .
Oh , thank you very much .
I 'll tell you what , why don 't we put it up somewhere where everyone can see it ?
- Yeah . - Where 's a good place ?
On the fridge in the kitchen .
- On the fridge ? - KIM : Yeah .
SARAH : There we go .
Will it be all right putting him up there , do you think ?
Yeah , because he likes everything freezing
and really cold .
Pam , there was something else , wasn 't there ?
Yes , there 's also this .
Once I looked in Suzie 's exercise book from school .
SARAH : Oh . PAMELA : I was so shocked ,
I said to her , " Did you write this ? "
I was going to hit her , I was so mad .
But it wasn 't me . I don 't even write like that .
Then I said to her , " Who was it , then ?
- " Who was it ? " - SARAH : Yeah .
Who or what ?
Michael .
Lots of questions there that need answering ,
perhaps we 'll have a chance to answer some of them tonight .
Just actually hearing in my earpiece that
Mike Smith has some news .
Mike , what 's happening ?
Thanks very much . Thank you .
I 've got eight or nine phone calls here
which are like Emma Stableford 's
we had earlier on .
They too have seen a mysterious dark figure
in the background of that shot in the children 's bedroom . Michael ?
" Dark , mysterious figure , " Doctor .
Have we got that sequence ready yet ?
- Yes . - Can we see that tape ?
Yeah , I think we can . I think we can see it
right now . Let 's roll the tape .
There you are , up there on the screen ,
that 's the tape you wanted , isn 't it ?
I can 't sleep . Turn the light off .
Mum said if you don 't ...
All right . All right .
MICHAEL : Now , this is the point where Emma Stableford ,
our caller , said she could identify that dark mysterious figure
in the corner of the room .
I don 't see anything myself , do you ?
DR PASCOE : Can we rewind it ? MICHAEL : Sure .
- Let 's rewind it . - Can we play it again ?
Can we play it back , BTL ? There you are .
Back a bit more .
- Yeah . Is that all right ? - Yeah .
- Can we go forward slowly ? - Sure , sure .
MICHAEL : All right . I 'm doing that now .
- That 's slow enough ? - Uh-huh .
I can 't see anything now myself . False alarm ?
Yeah , I think I can see what 's happened .
Do you see the shadow cast by the curtain there ?
- See on the curtain , on the left-hand side . - MICHAEL : Not really .
I tell you what we 'll do . We 've got a piece of ,
I don 't know ... Wheel that piece of sophisticated
technology in here .
You can actually use a light pencil on the screen there
just to identify exactly the area that you 're talking about .
- Is this it ? - Yes , that 's right .
Just draw on it as you would a normal pencil .
DR PASCOE : All right , I think ...
There 's a sort of shape there a face maybe ,
and a human form
I think the shadow 's caused .
I wonder if it 's that thing , you know , where you put your ...
Your dressing gown on the back of the bedroom door .
At a certain light , you look at it in the middle of the night
and it looks like a human form or face .
I mean , it 's easily done , isn 't it ?
I think that 's it . Exactly .
- " Faces in the fire . " - Yes .
Human perception is such that
the first thing you attempt to create
in any abstract shape is a human face or form .
Okay .
All right , then , well , I 'm sorry to disappoint you ,
but I 'll tell you what we 'll do ,
let 's go back over to Foxhill Drive
and learn about the toll that living there
has taken on the children 's mother , Pamela Early .
SARAH : Pam , I know this has all been a nightmare for you .
But what 's been the worst moment so far , do you think ?
I 'll show you .
I 've got to get this done properly .
My husband ... My ex-husband
used to develop his own photos in a darkroom under the stairs .
A " glory hole " , as we used to call it when I was a kid .
Why have you boarded it up like this then ?
PAMELA : Well ... ( SIGHS ) One night last January
I got it into my head
to try and find one of my letter ...
The solicitor 's letters about my divorce .
Erm , all of a sudden , the door stuck .
Like somebody was trying and pushing it from outside .
SARAH : You were inside by this time ?
Yeah .
I shoved , I tried to get out ,
and then I started to panic .
It was like a coffin , I couldn 't breathe .
I started screaming for Kimmy and Suzie ,
but all I could hear was my banging .
And all I could hear was Kimmy shouting ,
" It 's Pipes , Mum , Pipes . Pipes is here . "
SARAH : That 's awful .
The girls got you out eventually .
The thing is ,
when I was in there I swear , as God is my witness ,
I heard , I ...
Felt this man in there , with me ,
breathing right up against my face .
Like strong , like rotten cabbage .
I nearly died .
And ... And when I got out ,
my head went , my knees went .
Pam , let 's go sit down . Come on .
Tell us what happened next .
Well , after glory hole ,
erm , I wrote to the Council
to try and get us moved .
SARAH : Mmm-hmm .
But they wouldn 't take it seriously .
You know , like I was lying .
Just don 't want to know really .
We saw a social worker ,
and they said we should all see a psychiatrist .
Tell me what happened when the newspapers got their teeth into the story .
That was a disaster .
- Look at these . You got a lot of coverage . - Yeah .
" ' I believe in the Devil , ' says Spook House Mother . "
Did you say that ?
PAMELA : ( CHUCKLES ) No , I didn 't , no .
SARAH : Here 's " Power of Evil . "
PAMELA : Everyone was very friendly , but in the end ,
they all made us look even more like idiots .
So I went to the local TV .
- Can we have a look at that , actually ? - Yeah .
Here we are .
( INDISTINCT CHATTERING )
I told her it was the central heating .
So ever since then , she calls the noises " Pipes " .
So , Kim , aren 't you a little bit afraid ?
Sometimes .
MAN : ( ON TV ) Why ? Do you think Mr Pipes has come to hurt you ?
I think he 's come to hurt everybody .
I think he wants to do nasty things .
MAN : ( ON TV ) Okay . Thank you very much .
Now ...
Pam , thanks for letting us see that .
They 're ready for you now in the other studio .
- All right . - Yeah .
Pamela 's just going to make her way outside now to our mini-studio .
She 'll be there waiting to take your calls .
In the meantime , let 's go back to our main studio .
And , Sarah , thank you very much indeed .
Dr Pascoe , what was your introduction to the Early family ?
DR PASCOE : Well , I saw that programme
that we 've just seen an extract from
and I offered to help if I could .
MICHAEL : When you met Mrs Early then ,
was she then at the end of her tether ?
Yes , I 'd had some experience of a fairly violent poltergeist case
in Heidelberg , Germany .
So , I knew what it could do to a family , emotionally .
I see . Well , I believe that Mrs Early has joined us now .
Pamela , hello . Thanks for joining us .
- Hello . - MICHAEL : Yeah .
And thanks also for allowing our cameras into your home .
That can 't have been an easy decision to have taken .
Well , Suzanne was getting fed up with the jibes she was getting at school .
Erm , with the papers calling us liars and everything .
And she said , " Mum , Dr Pascoe wants us to do this BBC thing .
" So , let 's do it . And let 's show everyone ,
" and then , they 'll have to believe us . "
Erm , Pamela , I understand that you 're quite keen to share
your experience with our callers .
Yes .
And I want to tell everyone that , erm ,
they 're not going mad like I thought I was sometimes .
- That 's right . - All right .
Well , we 've got some callers on the line now .
Let 's take our first caller . Mike Smith , who is it ?
This is Sandra Hughes from Sussex .
Right . Let 's pick up the phones , Dr Pascoe .
Sandra , hello .
SANDRA : ( ON PHONE ) Oh , he ... Hello .
This is just that when I was a girl ,
I was brought up in a house in Brighton ,
and we had a ghost .
And we 'd often find things broken
and , you know , those sorts of things .
You 're not alone , Sandra , honestly .
SANDRA : ( ON PHONE ) And it 's sort of coming out about this boy who died there ,
and how it 's affected me .
Because at the time , I didn 't realise how much it affected me .
That 's ... That 's all I wanted to say , really .
Thank you , Sandra , for your call . Thanks a lot .
Thank you too , Mrs Early , for joining us .
Well , if you 'd stay in the studio , then we 'll come back to you in just a moment .
There are one or two other things to talk about first of all .
Thanks a lot .
Now , what I want to talk about now , Dr Pascoe ,
is this book of yours , which I 'll show to the camera there .
This is called Angels of the Odd .
And it 's a book that you wrote ,
your account of your investigation into this case .
And you also made a film at the same time .
We 've got an extract from the film .
Perhaps you could talk us through what 's happening here .
- MAN : All right ? - Yeah .
DR PASCOE : Well , we did extensive interviews .
And we also used the Ganzfeld technique .
MICHAEL : That 's what we 're seeing now .
And that 's where all the senses ...
Sensory inputs are blocked off .
DR PASCOE : Deprived , yeah . MICHAEL : Deprived , yes .
And you just feed in the white sound ...
DR PASCOE : Yeah . MICHAEL : White noise , through the headphones there .
DR PASCOE : Bright light . MICHAEL : Yeah .
DR PASCOE : Now , that 's when we would hear the voice .
" The voice " ? Well , we should hear the voice actually .
Let 's hear it now . Because this is intriguing .
Across here .
I should say that this tape is completely undoctored .
There 's no edit on it whatsoever .
All right . We should also warn our viewers of a nervous disposition
that there are things on this tape that they might find a little bit distressing .
At one point , we filled Suzanne 's mouth with coloured liquid ,
and we sealed her lips with tape ,
and the voice continued with absolutely no change in quality whatsoever .
Let 's hear it .
( PLATES CRASHING )
WOMAN : The window above the sink 's just been shattered now .
There 's no ... Oh , my God !
Look , the chair has gone .
( GIRL SCREAMING )
GIRL : She 's coming towards me , Mum !
WOMAN : It 's coming across the kitchen floor .
GIRL : Oh , my God ! Mum !
( PANTING )
WOMAN : It stopped . It 's suddenly stopped moving .
And everything seems to have gone quiet now .
( GHOST GRUNTING )
WOMAN : A grunt or something like that .
If you can grunt , can you speak ?
GHOST : Round and round the garden ...
WOMAN : Oh , dear God , save us .
GHOST : ... goes the teddy bear .
One stone ,
two stone , take her ...
WOMAN : Who are you ?
What 's your name ?
- ( GHOST TALKING INDISTINCTLY ) - WOMAN : Jesus Christ ! Are you joking ?
GHOST : ( BREATHING HEAVILY ) Very funny .
WOMAN : Are you dead ?
Are you in heaven ?
GHOST : All good children go to bed .
( GHOST CONTINUES INDISTINCTLY )
Bizarre . And chilling too .
Well , forensic scientists at Cambridge examined the voice recording ,
and compared it to Suzanne 's normal speech pattern .
And they defined it as the voices of two separate people .
Two people , yeah .
- And , erm , we asked Suzanne to see , if she could ... - Oh , my God !
DR PASCOE : ... imitate the voice recording .
And she was unable to do so for more than a few seconds .
MICHAEL : That 's her , trying it there . DR PASCOE : Yeah .
- Try it again . - ( IMITATING GHOST ) Round and round the garden
like a teddy ... Oh , my God .
- MICHAEL : She can 't do it . - No . Even under hypnosis , we tried that .
- Really ? And the same result ? - Still the ...
What other evidence do we have , Doctor ?
Well , over the months , Alan Demescu , my partner , and I heard numerous noises ...
Thuds , bangs , scratching on the walls , knocking .
The sort of normal noises you associate with poltergeist activity ?
What about this here , though ?
Ah , well , this is ... This is my favourite , I think .
This pillow moved diagonally to within about a foot of my face .
Now , it 's impossible to fake that . How do you fake that ?
MICHAEL : ( CHUCKLING ) I don 't know really at all .
Let 's have a look at some more evidence over here .
This is the wreckage evidence , if you like .
This is an extraordinary assembly of ...
- There is this cup here for instance . - Yeah .
Right ? Let me show that in the camera there .
Now , how did these breakages occur ?
- Were they dropped ? - DR PASCOE : Well , no ...
- The army did some analysis of this for us . - Yeah .
And they said it 'd been caused by intense temperature change .
Not by impact or shock .
MICHAEL : Really ?
- This temperature ... There you are . - DR PASCOE : Yeah .
MICHAEL : Look , the headless lady .
And lots more guys here , and crockery .
- Look at that . - DR PASCOE : Yeah .
And clocks or watches just stop when they 're in the house .
I mean , I just gave up wearing one . There 's no point .
MICHAEL : And the favourites in situations like this ...
God , the spoons that are bent .
Quite remarkable .
Couple of regular little Uri Gellers , those sisters .
Yes , they weren 't even in the room sometimes .
You 'd just open the drawer and they are there .
- And you saw all this happen ? - Yeah , many times .
Many , many times .
Extraordinary .
Let 's now look at another piece of evidence , Doctor .
And that 's the situation where Suzanne 's face at times is
covered with marks , with lesions .
Before I talk to you about that ,
I 'd like to talk to Suzanne .
And I think that ...
Yeah , there they are .
- We 're on . Yeah . Here we are . - We 're going live over there .
So I 'd like to talk to Suzanne .
Suzanne , when did you first get these marks on your face ?
When did they first show ?
About July , the first one was .
It was horrible .
Well , I 'd just wake up and it would feel like someone was all over me .
And in fact , we 've got there , Dr Pascoe ,
we 've got some of the pictures that were taken there
of the face of that girl
with these extraordinary marks on them .
DR PASCOE : Alan and I watched them appear on her face ,
quite literally in front of our eyes .
MICHAEL : There 's another shot there . Look .
Remarkable .
Now we 've seen , Dr Pascoe ...
We 've seen the evidence that you 've collected so far .
I 'd like your theory .
From what we 've seen , do you think that the
poltergeist activity , such that it is ,
is now centred on Suzanne ?
Well , certainly as a female approaching puberty ,
she does conform to the classic typical poltergeist focus .
- Yeah . - Broken family background ,
she 's introverted .
She tends maybe to direct her stress and anxiety inwards
until it has nowhere to go , and then ... Bam .
I see .
I think we 've still got Mrs Early there , in our outside broadcast studio .
If she 's ... Yes . There you are .
Mrs Early , I don 't know quite if you heard that ,
what Dr Pascoe was saying .
Well , she said that Suzanne was the classic typical poltergeist focus .
She was the person that all this energy was focusing on .
What do you think about that ?
Well , there 's nothing wrong with my Suzie . I know that .
If my Suzie 's funny , well , how does that explain the other things like , erm ,
like the glory hole ? It doesn 't and it can 't .
So you disagree with Dr Pascoe 's theory that
Suzanne 's psychological problems are the cause of these disturbances .
I think what you 're saying really is , in fact , that you believe it 's a natural ghost .
Don 't you , Lin ?
Pam , I 'm not disagreeing with you .
Please believe me . I 'm on your side .
I know that there 's something there .
I 'm just trying to understand what it is .
A poltergeist can be location-based or person-based .
I mean , who knows ? Maybe this is both .
I mean , of course a lot of people would have it that there 's nothing there at all .
Yeah , well , a lot of people would have it at one time that you couldn 't walk on the moon .
All right . Well , in order to avoid any accusations of bias ,
I 'd like to bring in physicist Emilio Sylvestri .
A former member of the sceptic society , CSICOP ,
the Committee for the Scientific Investigation for Claims of the Paranormal .
He 's in New York .
Good evening , Dr Sylvestri .
Good evening .
Thank you for joining us . You 've looked at the evidence in this case .
I 'd like to hear your conclusions . What are they ?
Well , I think it 's pretty obvious
there 's nothing in the tape that couldn 't be faked .
The bedroom footage is totally inconclusive .
It could all be done with wires , for all we know .
DR PASCOE : And the legions on Suzanne 's face ?
Scratched by her fingernails .
DR PASCOE : She 's not lying . Believe her .
I 'd love to .
The same as I 'd love to believe I 'm going to heaven ,
but ... Doesn 't make it a scientific fact .
DR PASCOE : But if people do believe in something ,
surely , we shouldn 't discount it .
I mean , it 's all part of human experience and that 's what we 're studying .
Well ... Fine , fine .
But is it measurable ?
Is it provable ? No ...
For years , parapsychologists have been trying to prove their loony theories
in laboratory conditions ,
and they can 't .
Yeah , that 's right . We can 't . That 's where we went wrong .
There are some things you can 't demonstrate in a lab .
Show me falling in love in a lab .
Show me poetic inspiration in a lab .
You can 't . You 've got to get out of the lab and into real life ,
and that 's what we 're trying to do tonight .
These people are not deceiving us or themselves . Look at them .
They 're in trauma for God 's sake . Why would they do it to themselves ?
The Early family are suffering just like people who 've had murder bereavements ,
or plane crashes .
The only difference is that nobody says that they don 't believe in plane crashes .
But most of us don 't believe that people come back from them .
See , that 's ...
What you 're always forgetting , Emilio , is that you have a belief system , too .
Your belief system is blanket denial .
You joke about it because you 're afraid to face it .
( SCOFFS ) That old chestnut .
Look , Lin , you ought to be selling crystals on Venice Beach ,
or palm reading ,
or a counsellor , a confidant , a guide maybe .
But a scientist ? I don 't think so .
MICHAEL : Dr Sylvestri , for the moment , thank you very much indeed .
I hope you 'll stay with us in our studio in New York ,
and keep an eye on what 's happening here ,
and from time to time , give us a comment on proceedings .
Thanks for joining us .
Well , there you are , Lin .
What do you think about that ?
CSICOP people have nothing to do with parapsychology .
They 're just a sign of the times .
In what way ?
They 're the last of the materialists .
Like the last of the dinosaurs .
The world 's changing .
Good doctor made you cross , didn 't he ?
No .
Right . Do or do now . Let 's go straight over to Sarah in Foxhill Drive .
Hang on .
Sarah , what 's happening there ?
It 's quite quiet , actually .
A bit too quiet .
Though , I must say , earlier on ,
Suze turned off Dr Sylvestri .
I don 't think she was that enamoured .
What does he know ? He 's not here .
MICHAEL : Well , in the moment we 've got here now , Sarah ,
perhaps you could tell us that ghost story you told us about earlier on .
Oh , yes , all right .
Well , it was sort of a ghost story .
- It happened ... - I can start another one .
A couple of months ago now .
We were staying at some friends of ours ' home .
They live in the Cotswolds .
Beautiful 15th , 16th century house .
And one night ,
I was woken up by the sound of this harpsichord music .
It was like chamber music .
But , you know , when a noise comes into your dream ,
and you 're not quite sure it 's in the dream ,
or whether it 's actually happening .
It was that kind of effect .
But it woke me up nonetheless .
And when I tried to get back to sleep again ,
I could still hear it .
But all I could see was this Indian woman 's face .
And she had her hair sort of pulled across her forehead and then tightly back .
And kohl around her eyes .
And her eyes were going from side to side .
You know , like in Indian dancing .
And slowly , the eyes lifted up and rolled right back until they were white ,
and then the face went .
The next morning , I couldn 't wait to tell everybody about this .
And the people whose house it is ...
They told me that the house had once belonged to the viceroy of India .
And he had had two Indian concubines living in the house with him .
And when they died ,
he couldn 't bury them in consecrated ground .
He wasn 't allowed to . So he buried them out in his garden .
And there had been talk in the village
of actually digging up the grave to see what else was down there .
And it became very clear to me that this was a sort of message to say ,
" No , don 't . They mustn 't do it . "
And so , when I found out that they weren 't in fact planning to do anything with the grave ,
they wouldn 't dream of it ,
I went back up to the bedroom ,
and I just sort of said , " Don 't worry . Nothing 's going to happen . "
And it was as though the atmosphere changed straightaway .
I have to say Smithy was a bit scared the next night .
He wouldn 't admit it , but he was .
But nothing happened .
And it was as though everything had gone calm again .
But the important thing here , it wasn 't scary . At all .
I mean , the music and the vision was very beautiful .
But ... That 's why I wanted to do this programme .
' Cause it 's intriguing .
- You all right ? - ( WHISPERING INDISTINCTLY )
Okay , yeah .
Kim just wants to go to bed now . It 's a bit late .
What time do you normally go to bed ?
- 8 : 00 . - 8 : 00 . Come on then .
You must be a bit tired .
KIM : Say hi to Mum .
SARAH : You want to just say hi to Mum ? Okay .
Well , tell you what ? If you look up to that camera there ...
- Yeah . Little thing there . - That ?
And you 'll be speaking to her , Kim . Say good night to her .
- Good night , Mum . - Good night , love . Sweet dreams .
Good night , Kim .
DR PASCOE : Remember , there 's nothing to be scared of .
To bed .
You really think there 's nothing to be scared of ?
SARAH : There we are .
Well , one says , the paranormal 's no more scary than
the weather or the tides .
I mean , all those things can harm us .
But we can also understand them .
All right ? Can I leave that light on ?
- Yeah . Good night . - All right . Good night .
- Keep warm . - Yep .
MICHAEL : So , Sarah , got anything to report at all ?
No . Nothing .
Just the cold .
It 's typical , isn 't it ?
A house full of technology , and nobody 's bothered to find out
whether central heating switch is on .
You okay , Suzanne ?
- Yes , I am . - Got your crisps ?
- Yeah . - Yeah ? Good . All right .
Now , guys , I think we 've earned ourselves a cup of coffee , don 't you ?
MAN : Yeah .
Pam told me where everything was , so ...
It 's just there .
Mike , how do you take the coffee ?
MIKE A : Black , one sugar please .
SARAH : Okay . What about you , Chris ?
CHRIS : Milk , one sugar please .
There we are .
You know what ?
I think I 'd almost feel happier if something was happening .
It 's sort of eerier just waiting , really , don 't you find ?
MIKE A : Well , I think , I might 've heard something earlier . Sort of ...
Just like an animal scratching its feet , but
they don 't record in this camera at all .
- Really ? - MIKE A : Yeah .
CHRIS : And I noticed earlier my watch had stopped .
- Really ? - CHRIS : Yeah .
What time ? When ?
CHRIS : Er , just before we went on air .
DR PASCOE : I said watches have a hard time .
Par for the course I 'm afraid .
I 'm fine .
Just as long as we all know , eh ?
MICHAEL : Don 't spook yourself .
No , it 's all right .
That 's what we 're being paid for .
We 're okay , anyway . Look .
We 've got an old hand to help us over here .
Now I just put the kettle on . Do you want a cup of tea or coffee ?
- No , thanks . I 'm having orange juice , okay ? - All right .
Can you get me a glass please ?
- SARAH : Where ? They 're just up here in the cupboard . - Yeah , that 's right .
While you 're in the fridge , just pass me some milk .
Yeah . Sure .
Whoo .
A balancing act . There we are .
- Mum ! - Hello , love . Are you all right ?
Yeah , I 'm fine . Are you all right ?
Yes .
MICHAEL : Well , there we are . So far , so good .
Now as you know , we asked you to join our
exploration of the supernatural by telling us your ghost story .
Well , here 's someone with a tale to tell ,
who wants to conceal his identity .
We had this dreadful day , er ,
that first evening .
with duvets being tugged off me .
Except for being quite amusing , we 'd been laughing about it .
It wasn 't at all malevolent or nasty .
But this particular day , it certainly was .
One of the first incidents that day ...
We were eating lunch and ...
I think it was mackerel or something like that .
We both looked down , this is my half-sister and me ,
and saw what looked like saliva
all over the mackerel .
Of course we couldn 't eat it .
And shortly after that ,
I found again what looked like saliva on the front doorstep .
Erm ...
I start ... I lost my temper with it .
For the first time , I say " it . "
This presence , whatever it was ...
And I started shouting and swearing .
And immediately , again , spit ...
What looked like spit appeared on my shoes .
As if in retaliation .
And either shortly before or shortly after this ...
Literally was disgusting . ( STAMMERING ) We found excrement smeared
on a cupboard door in the bathroom .
We had already , in fact found , er ,
such things in various parts of the flat .
This was the first time we actually found anything smeared like that on the door .
So it had to be cleared up . It was really horrible .
And from someone who believes in ghosts
to someone who 's not quite sure .
Let 's join Craig Charles .
Boo !
I bet that scared you , didn 't it ?
No , this is not a mask . This is Craig Charles , live , you lucky people .
And here we have the thrill-seekers .
Pillars of the community .
All waiting to see if the ghost is going to arrive .
Welcome to Fright Night .
Now I 'm gonna give you a little guided tour of the community .
And we 're gonna meet some people who are pretty upset about some weird goings-on .
And we 're gonna go to a pretty sinister place .
Let 's break into a little bit of a jog , lads .
Gets me fit , this jog .
That 's why I told Michael , I hate Halloween .
I hate apples . I hate dud apples .
I hate little kids all dressed up in ... Like the devil .
I 'm going to meet this woman , Yvonne Etherly .
And she 's on this piece of waste ground here , I think .
And then she 's gonna tell us some pretty peculiar things .
Erm , Yvonne Etherly .
Yvonne ? Which one ... You 're Yvonne .
Okay . Yvonne , can you ...
Can you tell me about some of the things that 've been going on around here ?
Well , we live opposite Pam at number 43 ,
and one night , ages ago now ,
we heard all this banging .
So we went to the front door ,
and it was obvious it was coming from Pam 's house .
CRAIG : So what did you see ?
Well , the top window was smashed ,
and Pam and Kimmy were in the garden crying .
So , we made them a cup of tea .
And they just come in into ours
whenever they need to , basically .
CRAIG : It all sounds a little bit weird .
What 's it like living in England 's Amityville ?
Well , it 's no joke .
I mean , it 's not very funny .
I mean , some really weird and horrible things happen around here .
CRAIG : Well , what kind of weird things ?
Well , there was that wee girl that went missing .
- Judy Weiland . - Judy Weiland .
It was in all the papers .
What happened to her ?
We don 't know . She just disappeared and then ...
Well , I know you 're always reading about people that were knifed and that sort of thing .
But somebody was knifed around here that was five years old .
CRAIG : Five years old ?
Okay . Can you tell me a little bit about this playground ?
Yeah .
Shall I go in ?
Yeah , yeah . Come on .
Well , it was this summer .
My ... My youngest son , Gary , came running into the house in a real state .
So , when I calmed him down , it seemed that they 'd been playing in here ,
and they 'd found this dead black Labrador .
Where did they find it ?
It was about here .
And how had it died ?
Well , it 'd been cut open , like something in a butcher 's shop .
Can you imagine the kind of person that would do something like that ?
Is that all that happened ?
Well , it was pregnant .
There were foetuses scattered all over .
The kids wouldn 't play for weeks .
I should imagine not .
So as you can see , this is a pretty sinister place .
Now I 'm gonna try and find the guy who tried unsuccessfully
to exorcise Foxhill Drive .
A Mr Arthur Lacey . Arthur Lacey ?
Arthur Lacey . Come with me , Arthur .
You got involved in your professional capacity , I believe .
ARTHUR : Well , not exactly .
By profession , I 'm a British Royal Guard .
CRAIG : Ah . But in your spare time , you 're a medium ?
ARTHUR : Well , I 'm a spiritualist . CRAIG : A spiritualist .
ARTHUR : Yes , and through God , I 've been given the task , when I can ,
to help spirits that may have lost their way .
So , you , erm ... You exorcised Foxhill Drive .
Well , it wasn 't the Ruituale Romanum , bell , book and candle .
No , I simply went and prayed with the family .
And offered a guiding light to whatever poor soul might need it .
And can you tell us what happened ?
You know how they say that
pigs can sense it before they get to the slaughterhouse ?
Well , I had this overwhelming sense of evil ,
of spiritual decay , is the only way I can describe it as .
Yeah , I was physically sick for a week .
I smelt blood on my hands .
Something didn 't want me near it .
Didn 't believe it was dead .
So do you believe there is such a thing as ...
I don 't know , an evil place ?
Well , there are degrees , yes , shades in all places .
I mean , anyone who buys a house finds themselves
weighing up these vibrations subconsciously .
You see , I think that
just as we are the product of our mothers and fathers and their mothers and fathers ,
I think that places somehow inherit the genes in their past too , somehow .
Yeah ?
Hey , trick-or-treaters I think .
- Hey , what 's your name ? - Katie .
- And your name ? - Billy .
Billy and Katie . Sounds a little bit like a ...
MICHAEL : Craig . Craig .
I 'm sorry to have to cut you off there .
In fact , I 've just heard that we 've got to go back to Sarah .
Sarah 's got something important for us .
Sarah ?
Yes , what is it ?
What have you got ?
Yeah , we definitely got something here . Just look at this .
Now , can you see this ?
MICHAEL : I certainly can , clearly .
SARAH : Well , there 's no way it could 've gotten there .
I thought maybe an old tomcat had got in or something .
DR PASCOE : Sarah , when did you see this ?
Well , I took Suzanne up to bed ...
In fact , all of us went upstairs .
Erm , nobody was down here at all .
Ten minutes ago , it wasn 't here .
DR PASCOE : Sarah , have you got a handkerchief ?
Can you see if the light fitting is working ?
Thanks . That 's great .
Yeah , we 'll do that for you .
Better turn the light off first , hadn 't I ?
All right . Okay .
Here we go .
I 'll put this . This is strong enough to hold me .
There we are . ( EXHALES )
- DR PASCOE : Anything ? - Er ...
There 's nothing dripped off here , first of all .
DR PASCOE : No stains on the ceiling ?
Just see , if there 's anything ?
DR PASCOE : No ?
- Forced concrete . - SARAH : No , this is all completely dry .
DR PASCOE : So , it couldn 't come from below . Is there any smell , Sarah ?
SARAH : No , nothing .
DR PASCOE : Can you smell the hanky , maybe ?
See if there 's anything on that now .
Any odour ?
The hanky ? ( SNIFFS )
No , no , can 't smell anything at all .
DR PASCOE : No . Can you take a sample for us ?
Have you got anything that you could ...
Yeah , er , what can we use for a sample ?
Something to swipe it up .
CHRIS : I got a lens duster .
DR PASCOE : All right , that would do .
Yeah , we 're gonna use this to ... Can I give you this hanky ?
Great . There .
See if we can suck some of whatever it is up with this .
Here we are .
DR PASCOE : You see , look , it 's typical .
It 's typical poltergeist .
If you pour water from a jug , it 's almost impossible to ...
To avoid getting an erratic outline .
Now these pools are perfectly oval , they 're unbroken .
- SARAH : Good . - ( SUZANNE COUGHS )
SARAH : Oh , Suzanne .
MICHAEL : Is she all right ?
SARAH : You okay ?
Yeah , I 've just got a bit of a nippy tummy .
SARAH : Oh , let me get you some Eno or something , hang on .
Doctor , when they 've got those samples that we saw them taking there ,
er , what do you do with them when you get the sample ?
Well , we 'll test it to see if the calcium and the magnesium salts
match the hardness of the local tap water .
And where does it come from ?
Don 't know .
Can 't get any water out .
( BANGING )
( SCREAMS )
( LAUGHS )
( SIGHS ) Can 't get it off now .
There we are , soaked .
There you are , Suzanne .
Sorry I 'm all wet . Let 's go upstairs , shall we ?
Can I ask you now , Dr Pascoe ...
We 've had a look at what 's been happening there in the house .
What , in fact , do you make of what we see ?
Well , poltergeist activity has a pattern ...
A menu if you like , erm ...
First , there are the noises , the sounds and then water .
And then the third stage is physical phenomenon , moving objects .
And did you think that in fact what we 're seeing there
is something starting to happen in Foxhill Drive ?
Well , who knows .
MICHAEL : Well , we shall all find out . No doubt .
Things have been happening in our phone rooms .
We 've got another caller on the line now .
He 's Kevin Trip , from Neath .
Pick up your phone there , please , Doctor ,
let 's talk to Kevin .
- Hello , Kevin . - KEVIN : Hello .
MICHAEL : Yeah , hello . KEVIN : Hello .
MICHAEL : Do you have a story for us ?
KEVIN : Yeah , can you hear me ?
Yes , yes . I can hear you fine .
KEVIN : Yeah , I was just sitting here and stuff , er ...
You ain 't gonna believe this , I 'm telling you .
Well , you try us , Kevin .
KEVIN : Well , my mates were round to watch the videos
and we put on the programmes about ten minutes ago .
Erm , I had this sandwich ,
cheese and pickle sandwich it was .
- Oh , yes . - KEVIN : And it frightened me to buggery , it did .
I was minding my own business and this dirty grey plate sitting on the arm of my chair
- just dived off . - MICHAEL : Sure , Kevin .
None of us nowhere near it or nothing , mind .
It just leapt off with a mind of its bloody own , it did .
Kevin , erm ... How close were you to the plate ?
KEVIN : Miles away .
My mates , er , they went white , they went .
Yes , yes . All right , Kevin , I think I get the picture , certainly .
Thank you very much , indeed for calling .
I suppose in fact we should have been prepared for that .
I mean , it 's Halloween night , home brew time and all that .
I can see you 're not as sceptical as I am , Doctor , that 's all right .
But really , serious calls , please .
The lines are still open
and we 've got time for just one other call , I think .
No , in fact , we haven 't .
I 'm sorry , apparently we 've got to go straight back to Foxhill Drive , where ...
Things are happening , so
from here wasn 't it ? Did you hear ?
Yes , this way .
Are you picking this up too ?
Just put the light on .
( BREATHING HEAVILY ) You 're going to have to be ... Get it out here .
MIKE A : Move the bed .
SARAH : I 'll get that .
Are you all right ?
Listen , I 'll crawl down there , all right ?
( SCRATCHING NOISES )
Some scratching down here .
( SCRATCHING STOPS )
( MUFFLED FOOTSTEPS )
It 's moved .
MIKE A : It 's in the wardrobe .
Let 's just get this out of the way .
Can you hear this ?
- I can 't get it open . - ( BANGING )
( KIDS SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY )
We can hear him in the kitchen !
( ALL YELLING SIMULTANEOUSLY )
You just go back to bed .
( BANGING )
Back into bed . It 's downstairs . Come on .
It stopped . I can 't hear anything now .
What are these ?
( PANTING )
It 's all kids ' pictures . They weren 't here before .
- ( CAT MEOWS ) - ( EXCLAIMS )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
I didn 't know they had a cat .
Did you ?
- I don 't know what to do . Should we go back upstairs ... - MIKE A : Shh !
Shh !
( LOUD BANGING )
Upstairs . Children . Come on .
MICHAEL : Er , Sarah , stay where you are , please .
Sarah , stay there . Please , don 't go upstairs .
Why ?
MICHAEL : Because we hear that Suzanne 's got out of bed but she 's not yet ...
Stay here ? I don 't know why .
MICHAEL : She 's not appeared on the landing .
SARAH : Suzanne . Where ... Where is she ?
( BANGING CONTINUES )
DR PASCOE : It could be a piece of its usual misdirection . I just ...
Trust me , Sarah .
Stay there .
( BANGING CONTINUES )
Suzanne must still be in the bedroom .
MICHAEL : But where ?
DR PASCOE : Perhaps out of camera range , right in the corner of the room .
Can we cut to the wall camera ?
No , sorry . Sorry , the landing camera .
No , the landing on the door .
- ( BANGING CONTINUES ) - The other landing . That 's it , and zoom in .
Can we pan ?
Can we pan left ?
And down .
( BANGING CONTINUES )
MICHAEL : Okay .
- ( SCREAMING ) - SARAH : Kimmy !
Come on .
Kimmy .
Suzanne , are you okay ?
Are you all right ? Come on .
- It wasn 't me . - It doesn 't matter .
- It wasn 't me ! - It doesn 't matter !
MICHAEL : Oh , that 's , that 's quite extraordinary .
We set out to catch a ghost and ...
And sadly , very sadly , what we witnessed was a remarkable
exposure of a hoax .
Let 's not be too hasty .
Oh , come on , Doctor . Please ,
- we 've surely got to accept we saw it there . - DR PASCOE : No , I don 't .
Look , this is an established pan .
Genuine phenomena followed by the fakery stage
when the children feel obliged to come up with the goods .
Doctor , really ?
I 'm sorry , because ...
Well , I mean , after eight months of commitment
and connected work like you 've been through ,
I can understand you feel upset because you 've been duped .
I 'd be the first to admit it if it was absolutely sure I had been duped .
Oh , Doctor , really ...
Please don 't be simplistic .
This is one incident amongst many .
Many dozens .
I was there . I 've seen them .
I 've seen inexplicable things .
One-hundred percent , no question .
And this ?
Let 's not get sidetracked , please .
Let ... Let 's not lose the scent .
Maybe there 's a kind of ...
Ritualistic reason , it 's like sympathetic magic .
Acting out what they want to happen .
The invoking process
that proceeds the genuine appearance .
Doctor , before we get too involved in that kind of jargon ,
let 's see what Suzanne has to say about this .
She might ... Sarah , is Suzanne able to speak to us ?
Suzanne needs a glass of water right now .
DR PASCOE : Can I talk to her ?
MICHAEL : Well , I think I 'd like to talk to her first of all
if you don 't mind .
Where 's my mum ?
MICHAEL : Suzanne , I 'd like to talk to you .
Did you put the writing in your schoolbook ?
SUZANNE : ( TEARFULLY ) I don 't want to talk about it .
MICHAEL : What about the noises in the wall ?
SUZANNE : I don 't want to talk about it !
MICHAEL : What about the scratches on your face , Suzanne ?
- ( SOBS ) Mum . - It 's all right , child . Your mum 's here .
Doesn 't matter . Can you look at me ?
DR PASCOE : Why , Suzie ? You can tell me .
SUZANNE : To show them .
DR PASCOE : Well , you didn 't have to show them . Not like this .
Hmm ? Why ?
Tell them you don 't tell lies , Suzie .
It 's all a mistake .
She doesn 't know what ... She doesn 't know anything .
Do you , love ?
I thought you 'd leave us .
DR PASCOE : You thought I 'd leave you ?
All we were , were noises to you .
DR PASCOE : And you lied to make us stay ?
Sometimes .
MICHAEL : Only sometimes ?
It was what you wanted , wasn 't it ?
We just gave you what you wanted !
KIM : Stop it !
MICHAEL : Mrs Early , you 've heard your daughter .
She 's admitted the entire thing was a deliberate fraud .
No , I 'm sorry , I don 't accept that .
Dr Pascoe has seen in her things , same as me .
- You can 't just ... - MICHAEL : But ...
Well , she 's afraid , she 's frightened .
- She doesn 't know anything . - MICHAEL : But , Suzanne herself explained , Mrs Early .
My family are telling the truth .
We 're all telling the truth .
Well , fortunately , after this turn of events ,
we 're able to return to Dr Emilio Sylvestri .
Dr Sylvestri , who 's in New York , joins us again now .
Dr Sylvestri , I imagine you 're about to say ,
" I told you so . "
Well ... ( CHUCKLES )
I ... I don 't get any vicarious thrill
out of seeing parapsychology crucified in public .
But it does ...
Validate my hypothesis .
Hmm , what hypothesis ?
These are disturbed attention-seekers ...
Oh , rubbish .
We ... ( SNICKERS ) . You played into their hands .
Primetime TV Alice in Wonderland , couldn 't take it any more , they ...
- End of illusion ... - This is not the end , please believe me .
I almost ... I almost feel , whatever is in there , it 's
deliberately muddying the waters .
Well , Dr Pascoe , thank you . And Dr Sylvestri , thank you , too , for joining us
from New York . Thank you and ... And good night to you .
A lot of activity in our phone room .
You won 't be amazed to hear that after what we 've just seen in Foxhill Drive .
Er , Mike Smith , what 's happening ? What 's the story ?
( HESITATINGLY ) Well , the strange thing is
that we 're still getting calls about that shadowy figure ,
that was seen in the haunted bedroom
or people think they 've seen in the haunted bedroom . Now ...
What 's really weird is that these are all tallying with the description .
These are all different phone calls .
They 're , generally , all saying that it 's an old man
or a woman .
Er , bald with a skull-like head ,
dark eyes ,
or some are just saying , " Holes for eyes . "
Wearing a black robe or a dress which is buttoned up to the neck .
So , if anybody 's seen this gentleman tonight ...
Michael , I 'm sorry to interrupt , but this is important .
Er , can somebody in the gallery , tell me if it 's possible
to access the tape interviews I 've shot at the university , please .
I 'm sure , I 'm sure it will be , yes , erm ...
In view of what 's happened there 's a sequence I need to find , urgently .
Yeah , they 're saying they can ... They can get to it
sometime further on the programme .
Yes , okay . We can do that for you .
Erm , in the meantime we 'll have another Ghostwatch story .
And then after that , I 'd like to hear your opinion
on what we saw , a moment ago , in Foxhill Drive .
Is all of this , all of this , a hoax
or as Dr Pascoe believes ,
are things just about beginning to happen ?
Well , call me after this true ghost story , coming up now .
When I was about eleven or twelve ,
we moved to this large , old Devonshire house .
And part of the house is a lot older than the other part of the house .
And it had a nasty feeling .
It was cold .
Erm , things ...
Doors opened , things fell off the wall , ornaments shattered ,
and generally , it didn 't have a nice feeling .
Erm , my bedroom was in part of that house .
Part of that , old part of the house . And , er ...
Shadows would move at the end of my bed .
So , I asked for a night light .
I asked a grown-up , I think it was my grandmother .
Erm ... Which made the situation worse in a way , because ...
( AUDIO SLOWING DOWN )
- ( TAPE REWINDING ) - ... in a way .
Wait , wait . Can we just clear the set ? ( SNICKERS )
Yeah , well something 's gone very wrong with that ghost story ,
probably a poltergeist . What do you think , Dr Pascoe ?
Anyway , erm , we 'll try to get back to that , er ...
Before the end of the programme . Er , meanwhile , what do we do ?
We go back to your calls , that 's what we 'll do .
Erm , Mike Smith ?
( HESITATING ) Erm , the only one I got for you at the moment ,
is this woman , try ... Try her .
She wants to remain anonymous .
Wants to take part in the programme , but insists on anonymity . Try her .
Okay , Mike , thanks . Doctor , pick the phone up .
- Hello ? - WOMAN : ( ON PHONE ) Hello .
- Yes . - WOMAN : Hello , am I on ?
Yes , You 're , er ... You 're on BBC One 's Ghostwatch .
Now , what do you want to tell me about ?
WOMAN : ( SIGHS ) We 've got this big glass table .
My husband just rested one finger on it and it exploded .
Glass everywhere ,
his face and hands were cut .
There 's blood on the wallpaper .
The ambulance is just gone .
My children are frightened . Why are you doing this ?
Now look , I am sure your children are in shock . Er ...
Also want to say , I think , it 's high time , probably ,
that your kids are in bed .
I mean , it is past the 9 : 00 watershed , isn 't it ?
WOMAN : That 's it . That 's just it .
They won 't go to bed .
I can 't drag them away from the TV .
I tell them to look at what time it is
but the clock still shows 9 : 30 .
Excuse me , have all your clocks stopped ?
WOMAN : I don 't know what 's going on .
They won 't take their eyes , off the set .
( CRYING ) And there 's blood ...
There 's blood all over the wallpaper .
Look , love , it 's Halloween . They 're overexcited .
Er , you 've had a terrible accident . Now ...
Now , please , would you switch off the TV and please , send your kids to bed .
Thanks for calling us , but we 've got to move on . Thank you , love .
No , don 't let her ...
I 'm sorry , she 's gone .
Erm , listen , please ...
If you 're still there .
Don 't touch anything , and if you can , take a photograph .
Now , this is very valuable evidence .
I 've got to say to everyone watching .
Please , please , we don 't want to give anybody sleepless nights .
We don 't want to start panic .
Don 't let your imaginations run riot .
These things we 're talking about are very , very rare , indeed .
And the chance of them happening to you are exceedingly remote .
Er , please , believe us .
Right , now I think that Dr Pascoe , that that tape you wanted ,
that interview you did some months ago with Kim Early ,
I think that 's ready now . I think we can go to it .
It 's coming up now . There you are .
So , have ever seen him then , Kimmy ?
Pipes ? Yeah .
And what does he look like ? Can you describe him to me , then ?
Well , he 's really old .
And this eye 's got all blood over his eye and scratch coming out and then ...
- He 's bald over his head . - Mmm-hmm .
And then he 's got a nose .
And in the middle , it 's got a scratch all the way down .
- Hmm . - In there .
- And he 's got a dress on . A dress on . - Does he ?
Yeah . It 's really long and it 's black .
- It 's got buttons , all the way down . - Hmm .
- And then lots of petticoats underneath . - DR PASCOE : Can we replay it ?
- MICHAEL : Sure , sure we can . - DR PASCOE : Back to the start of the description .
All right , can we roll it back , BTL ?
Back to the start of it .
( TAPE REWINDING )
- There ? - Well , he 's really old .
And this eye 's got all blood over his eye and scratch coming out and then ...
- He 's bald over his head . - Mmm-hmm .
Now , do you see what I mean ? Kim 's description exactly matches
what Mike 's been getting on the phones .
" Old , man ,
" bald , he 's got a skull-like head , dark eyes ,
" wearing a black dress . "
- KIM : It 's black . - She says it 's black .
- KIM : All the way down . - Buttoned .
Well , could they have read the descriptions in a newspaper , perhaps ?
There 's been nothing in the newspapers , not containing that description .
It 's not appeared in print one single time , I assure you .
Then what are you saying ?
Well , we were drawn to assuming it was Suzanne at the centre of this
because she 's at puberty , but what if she isn 't ? What if it 's Kim ?
- We 've been looking at the wrong person . - DR PASCOE : Exactly .
Fascinating . ( CHUCKLES )
Er , Sarah seems to be trying to get our attention ,
er , quite agitated . Sarah , what is it ?
Thank you . It 's Pamela . Listen to this .
Cats . It 's like cats .
- Can you hear it ? - MICHAEL : Where , Pam ?
It 's all ... It 's all around us .
Like they 're trapped , somewhere . Do you hear it ?
( CAT MEOWING )
Cats running round up there on the ceiling .
- MICHAEL : Can you hear anything , Sarah ? - Yes .
Yeah , I can hear it , now . She 's right .
- KIM : Mum ? - PAMELA : What is it , Kimmy ?
( CATS MEOWING LOUDER )
KIM : What 's wrong with Suzie ?
What do you mean ? What 's wrong , Kimmy ?
- PAMELA : Suzanne ? - ( SUZANNE MOANING )
SARAH : Suzanne , are you okay ?
PAMELA : It 's all right , love . Don 't get upset , love . Your mum 's here .
- ( CRYING ) Oh , dear God . - SARAH : Oh , God !
SARAH : What do you want us to do ?
- MICHAEL : Sarah , Sarah ? Are you all right ? - What should we do ? ( GASPS )
- Get away ! Get away from ... - No Mum , they have to stay . They have to see everything .
DR PASCOE : Sarah , it 's all right . Don 't worry .
It 's some kind off allergenic psychosomatic reaction .
MICHAEL : Could be self-mutilation .
She could 've done it with her own fingernails , you know ?
SARAH : They say that she used her own fingernails for this .
" Fingernails " ?
What flaming fingernails ?
( KIM CRIES OUT )
Now , what do you want us to do ?
DR PASCOE : Sarah , don 't worry . I 've seen it before . It will subside .
Feel her temperature .
- SARAH : She 's burning up . - Get off me . Don 't touch me .
SARAH : It 's like a meat locker in here . It 's so cold .
Well , we can 't move her , because she is in agony
and she won 't even let me touch her .
SARAH : What do you want me to do .
PAMELA : Yeah , get a flannel and get some water .
SARAH : Yeah , come on . We 'll get out of here , come on .
- Sorry , I didn 't mean to drag you out . - CHRIS : It 's okay .
I just think they need a bit of time , here .
- ( GHOST SIGHS HEAVILY ) - SARAH : Oh , God !
- CHRIS : What is it ? - ( GASPING )
SARAH : Behind the door .
SARAH : I ...
I saw somebody standing behind the door .
CHRIS : Nobody there now .
Sorry .
- Pam , here we are . - KIM : Pipes says she 's got to be punished . She 's a bad girl .
It 's all right . Just be quiet .
MIKE : Oh , good God . Sarah , should we send someone in , now ?
SARAH : No , God knows how she 'd react .
- Just let ... Let 's , let everything settle down now . - ( SUZANNE MUMBLING )
- What , darling ? - We 've got to stay . Pipes says we 've got to stay .
Okay , okay .
I should tell you , if you 've joined
to see the next programme that in fact we 're staying
with what we have here from Foxhill Drive , because the events are ...
Are so remarkable and dramatic that we will be staying with them
for as long as we have to .
SARAH : Is it worse than it was before ?
MICHAEL : Doctor , what about ...
Your theory that ...
In fact , Kimmy was the focus
for the poltergeist activity .
What does this mean , now ?
DR PASCOE : Well , maybe they 're both involved .
I mean , maybe it 's like a tandem effect .
Kim 's creating the energy and Suzanne 's directing the violence in on herself .
First , Suzanne ,
then Kimmy ,
then this .
You don 't know , do you ?
No , I don 't .
SARAH : You know what , darling ...
MIKE : I 've got to come in here . We 've got a ...
A very important phone call which I think
you both should take right now .
Doctor .
Er , hello , who am I talking to ?
WOMAN : ( ON PHONE ) Oh , hello , my name is Mary Christopher .
And I just wanted to phone and tell you about this ...
Well ... About my mother , really .
We were Northolt born and bred .
And , erm , and as children , if we were naughty or couldn 't get to sleep ,
our mum used to say , " Mother Seddons will come to get you . "
It used to scare us rigid .
I don 't know why she 'd ...
Parents do do some awful and daft things , don 't they , Mary ?
MARY : Yeah , well , years later ,
I found out that she really did exist .
And she was a baby farmer , like a child minder .
She used to take kids in , but she used to kill them .
And she 'd drown them in the big coppers .
And why ... Why I 'm ringing is ,
she used to live in one of the old terraces
in Foxhill by the railway as it was then ,
and is now , Foxhill Drive ,
and I 'm just sure it 's where those poor girls live now .
And really , that 's all I have to say .
I just wanted to make sure you knew .
Thanks for your call , Mary .
Thanks very much for calling in .
Sarah , I wonder ...
Sarah , Sarah , did you hear any of that ?
Sarah , can you hear me ?
Could I talk to Sarah , please ?
Mike , it 's all right . I can hear you . I 'm fine .
Erm , Suzanne 's feeling a bit better now .
But we still don 't know how the scratches got on her face .
But , we feel it 's probably best to get the girls out of the house now .
Er , things are still ...
Feeling quite strange .
KIM : No , we 're not ! Get it off !
I 've got to talk to somebody .
Kimmy ? Who ?
Kim , who 're you talking to ?
Pipes .
SARAH : Where 's Pipes ?
Here .
SARAH : What does he look like , Kimmy ?
Like somebody 's mum .
MICHAEL : I 'd like both of those children out of that house .
- PAMELA : Kimmy , it 's time to go . - No !
MICHAEL : I 'd like somebody to take care of Suzanne as well .
Please , let 's have the kids out of the house .
- I want to speak to Pipes . - Leave me alone .
I 'm not a baby !
KIM : No , you lied , you said you 'd stay .
SARAH : We will stay with you .
- ( LOUD THUDDING ) - SARAH : What was that ?
KIM : Where 're we going ? SARAH : Come on .
SARAH : Just outside , come on .
Downstairs . Just outside . Come on .
( INDISTINCT CONVERSATION )
KIM : I don 't want to go .
Pipes says we 've got to stay .
Pipes wants to see everybody .
Look , everybody wants to see him .
MICHAEL : Hopefully , the children are on their way out of the house now .
And once they are , I suppose that 'll be the end
of our program , the end of our Ghostwatch programme .
I hope they ... They are out shortly .
Er , as we wait for them to come out ,
we 'll go over to our phone-in studio .
Mike , what 's been happening ?
MIKE : Er , well , it 's understandably fairly chaotic here .
Erm , we 're getting all sorts of calls .
In Derby , someone was ringing to say that her clock had stopped .
MICHAEL : Again , a clock stopping .
A Ken and Joyce Shrivener from Telford in Shropshire ,
their radio has gone dead .
And the microwave oven is pinging repetitively .
Well , where are they happening ?
I mean , is there a geographical pattern ?
How many of these incidents are there ?
I don 't know , I don 't know how many of these to take with a pinch of salt .
Mrs Pinder from Chepstow , her dog won 't stop barking .
Er , in fact , we have loads of instances recorded here , this evening ,
of pets acting up all through the programme .
Mr Naro from Cheltenham ,
says his son is making glasses break .
I 'm sure we can assume that many , if not all of these calls , are jokes .
I 'm more interested in what 's happening at the house .
Are they all out yet ?
MIKE : No , no , wait , wait , wait .
We 've got one here that , erm ...
Just in the last few minutes , a young lady , very distressed ,
in response to something that we showed earlier on .
And she 's hung up before we 'd had a chance to talk to her , so ...
The point is , there 's someone here who could take your call now .
We need to talk to you , could you call back ?
- Can we talk to these people ? - Let 's get back to Sarah .
Sarah ... Sarah , are you all right ?
Er , I 'm s ...
I can hardly hear you .
( AUDIO MUTES )
... you can hear what I 'm saying .
Erm , Suzanne 's a lot quieter now .
But , er ...
They ... They won 't move .
They won 't listen to me .
I think Suzanne 's in ...
In some kind of a state of shock .
What do I do ? I can 't leave them .
( LOUD FEEDBACK )
Sorry , I 've got to take this out .
- It 's a terrible noise . - ( LOUD BANGING )
( BANGING CONTINUES )
I don 't know what 's going on .
Can you hear this ?
Smithy ?
- Michael ? - ( FEEDBACK CONTINUES )
Dr Pascoe ?
( BANGING CONTINUES )
There are incredible noises coming from the walls .
And from the ceiling . ( SCREAMS )
- Oh . - Jesus .
Kimmy . Kim !
- You all right ? - Can 't you do something ?
( SHRIEKS )
Suzie .
( IN DEMONIC VOICE ) What big eyes you have . What big lips you have .
PAMELA : Stop it !
Stop it , Suzie !
Suzanne , you 're coming with me .
Suzanne ?
You 're coming ... Suzanne ?
Listen to me , Suzie .
Suzie ? Can you hear me ?
Suzanne , do you hear me ?
( IN OWN VOICE ) Yes .
Yes . Get out .
Get out if you don 't want to be here .
I don 't care .
You just mess things up .
You mess everything up .
I hate you .
SARAH : Kimmy !
Kimmy , if you can hear me ,
just shout .
Let me know where you are , so that we can help you .
Kimmy !
( PANTING )
Kim .
Just say something .
Kimmy ?
Kimmy !
Kim ?
( WATER RUNNING )
It 's her bunny .
The fridge .
Kimmy . Come on , darling .
- Hmm ? - Pipes said to do it .
- Why ? - Pipes says he 's a bad , bad bunny .
Here are his eyes .
( CATS SHRIEKING )
What 's that noise ?
( SHRIEKING CONTINUES )
All right , where is it coming from ?
MICHAEL : I 'm looking .
( RATTLING )
MICHAEL : This looks like an earthquake .
( CATS MEWLING )
- SARAH : Mike ... - ( MEWLING CONTINUES )
It 's in here . It 's in the glory hole .
SARAH : Can you just stay back over there , darling ?
Stay ... Stay over there .
It 's in there .
SARAH : Okay .
( CATS SHRIEKING )
SARAH : Just pull it aside .
( SARAH GRUNTS )
( CATS MEWLING )
SARAH : Shall I get them out of the kitchen drawer ?
( CATS SHRIEKING )
( SARAH GRUNTS )
Take this away . Yeah .
- ( CRASHING ) - SARAH : Mike ?
Oh , my God , what 's happened ?
Are you okay ? Look .
Chris , stay there . I 'm gonna go and get help , all right ?
- CHRIS : Okay . - Just stay there with him .
( SUZANNE SCREAMING )
Suzanne ...
SUZANNE : He 's touching me .
Suzanne ?
SUZANNE : He 's hurting me .
He 's hurting me .
Get off me ! Get away ! Get off me !
No ! Go away !
Mum , help me !
Don 't leave me , Mum ! ( SCREAMS )
MIKE : Have we ... Have we lost the link completely ?
MICHAEL : No , there 's nothing .
Hang on , yeah , we 're on .
MICHAEL : Please tell him . We 've honestly lost the link ?
Well , the red light 's on . We are definitely on .
- Sorry , there seems to be a bit of a ... - Okay , we can 't get it back .
Bit of a bold , in TV speak , I think we can say .
MIKE : You must be able to get it back somehow .
MICHAEL : Er , we 're finding out .
Well , nothing to report so far from the house .
- Eh ... - It all seems very quiet and peaceful .
To tell you the truth , I 'm not really bothered .
I didn 't really want the scoop on the Headless Horseman .
I mean , like , where do you put your microphone ?
( LAUGHING )
MICHAEL : Is somebody speaking to them ? What 's everybody doing up there ?
You 're following me around , kids , aren 't you ?
I think we 're off again now .
God . I wish someone would 've said we were on then .
You know , I 'm shouting away and ...
Only at the BBC , loves .
- DR PASCOE : Er , I think ... - What 's going on then ?
DR PASCOE : Okay , so somehow ... MICHAEL : Just a minute . Sorry .
MICHAEL : We 're back . Back in Foxhill Drive .
- Oh , fantastic . - DR PASCOE : God ...
MICHAEL : Still no sound , but it looks peaceful enough , doesn 't it ?
DR PASCOE : Yes , it does .
MICHAEL : Where 's the soundman ?
I assume they 've got him out , actually . Obviously .
And back to ... Back to normal .
They look happy .
Mike Smith 's right . He breathes a sigh of relief , no doubt .
( STAMMERS ) Yeah ... No , I 'm delighted ... I ...
I was ready to , erm ... I don 't know ...
Oh , panic over , hopefully .
Can we see the rest of the house ?
I 'm sure we can . I 'd like to talk to Sarah as well .
While we 're working on trying to talk to Sarah again ,
perhaps there 's time to take one of those many phone calls
that are stacking up . Mike ?
Yeah , I 'll be delighted to . Who is the next caller ?
Talk to him ...
- Hello . Your name is ? - MAN : ( OVER PHONE ) I don 't want to give me name .
But I think I have some information for you about the history of the house .
Well , what do you know about it ?
Well , we 've been into all that . We 've got the , er ,
the deeds and searches going back to the year it was built .
And the history of the site as far the Doomsday Book ,
and the , erm , the lay lines .
MAN : Do you know Mr and Mrs Sellers ?
Yes , they 're on our list of tenants .
They lived there in the ' 60s I think .
MAN : Did you know they sublet a room ?
No , I didn 't ... I didn 't know that .
MAN : Being illegal , it wouldn 't be on the official records .
The lodger was their nephew , Raymond Tunstall .
How do you know him ? And why are you calling , sir ?
MAN : I worked as his social worker
when he came out of psychiatric hospital .
He had several convictions for molestation ,
aggravated abuse , abduction of minors ...
He should never have been let anywhere near any community .
He was a very disturbed man in my opinion .
MICHAEL : In what way ?
MAN : From the time he moved to Foxhill Drive ,
he developed paranoid fantasies .
He used to tell me there was a woman on the inside of his body ,
taking over his thoughts and actions ,
making him do things he didn 't want to do .
He started to wear dresses .
The delusions got so bad ,
there was only one way to escape them .
He took his own life .
That 's why I called .
When I heard ...
When I was sitting here watching the TV and ...
Hello ? Are you still there ?
If you are , please go on . Hello ?
MAN : Tunstall hanged himself .
He tied a wire around his neck
to a lathe and switched it on .
He did it where he kept his tools , under the stairs .
His aunt and uncle were on holiday .
It was twelve days before anybody found him .
They heard the cats screaming .
He had about a dozen cats .
The cats were locked in , of course .
Of course ...
Twelve days ... They got hungry .
They got to work , on ...
On his face .
DR PASCOE : Mister ...
I 'm sure what you say is true .
We 've no reason to disbelieve you . But ... ( SIGHS )
In order to substantiate ...
MICHAEL : He 's gone .
Doctor , he 's ... He 's hung up .
Sorry , but that 's how it is . He 's gone .
Oh , dear ...
I think this is the onion skin .
- What is ? - ( SIGHS )
I mean , what happened on that spot ,
how many terrible things have ...
Oh , this has got to be nonsense , Doctor .
Before Turnstall , before Mother Seddons , way back ...
Maybe into prehistory ...
Oh , nonsense . There 'll be no more calls , please .
Also , our switchboard 's jammed .
We 've been inundated with hoaxes ...
The Rosenheim poltergeist affected a telephone exchange ,
rang up endless bills , misdirected calls
poltergeist or no poltergeist .
They are seeing it now , for God 's sake .
Don 't close the lines ! We need to know what 's happening out there !
You 're the expert ! What is happening out there ?
I don 't know .
- Jeez ... - MICHAEL : What is it ?
Doctor , what 's wrong ?
What 's the matter ?
It 's in the machine .
MICHAEL : Wh ... What ?
- Well , look at the picture . - Where ?
DR PASCOE : On the wall . The picture on the wall .
- MICHAEL : What about the picture on the wall ? - Well , it 's still there .
It hasn 't fallen .
It 's not come off the wall .
This picture we 're seeing now isn 't live .
This is some earlier footage from earlier in the evening .
This is just a cover .
- It 's a dupe . - ( MICHAEL STAMMERS )
DR PASCOE : This isn 't happening now .
MICHAEL : But what is happening ?
( SCREAMING )
( LOUD GROANING )
It 's what you wanted , wasn 't it ?
Well , we just gave you what you wanted !
- DR PASCOE : They don 't look very shocked any more . - KIM : Stop it ! Stop it !
MICHAEL : ... o f course the recorder isn 't shocked any more . You 're being silly .
( WIND HOWLING )
There 's a wind . Have you ever heard of
- in a studio ? - How many observers do we have tonight ?
- I don 't understand . - Jesus , Mike ,
we 've created a seance .
A massive seance .
MICHAEL : Where are we now ? What 's this ? This ...
( SIREN BLARING )
This could be live . Is this is happening outside the house ?
- I think it is . - The police ! The police ! The police !
( SIREN BLARING )
MICHAEL : We 've got to assume this is live , actually happening .
- DR PASCOE : Is that Kimmy ? Yes . - ( DOGS BARKING )
KIM : ( SOBBING ) Mum ! Mum !
MICHAEL : We 've seen ... We 've seen Mike come out .
We 've seen Kim .
We 've seen ... We 've seen Pam .
So that leaves Suzanne ...
And Sarah .
Now ... Now where are they ? Where can they be ?
- Have you seen them ? - DR PASCOE : Must be still in there .
MIKE : What are these shapes ?
MICHAEL : Where are we ?
MIKE : Look , what are we seeing here ?
DR PASCOE : The infrared camera .
DR PASCOE : Who 's that ? SARAH : Suzie ?
MIKE : It 's Sarah . DR PASCOE : Is it ?
SARAH : Suzie , are you there ?
MICHAEL : Can she hear us ?
SARAH : Chris ?
CHRIS : Down here .
- Where are you ? - CHRIS : Here .
Oh , my God , you 're there . Can you see if you can see her in that room ?
CHRIS : Hold on .
CHRIS : No , she 's not down here .
I know , Chris . Have you still got your lighter ?
CHRIS : Yeah .
Got it . There we are .
Oh ...
( CLATTERING )
There we go .
Is it okay for you ?
Is it okay ?
CHRIS : Yeah , hold on .
SARAH : Mmm-hmm .
Chris , look .
( CAMERA WHIRRING )
SARAH : Can you see them ? CHRIS : Yeah .
- ( WIND HOWLING ) - ( SARAH GASPS )
SUZANNE : Mum !
- ( ELECTRICITY CRACKLES ) - SUZANNE : Mum , help me !
Help me , Mum , please !
SARAH : It 's okay Suzie , we 're here !
Where are you ?
SUZANNE : Mum , help !
- Help ! - CHRIS : She 's downstairs . In the glory hole .
- ( CHRIS GRUNTS ) Shit . - SARAH : Chris , are you all right ?
CHRIS : Yeah . SARAH : Hang on .
SUZANNE : Get off me ! Get away !
SARAH : It 's all right , Suzie .
SUZANNE : Get off me .
Get away !
SARAH : Come on .
Suzie ?
SUZANNE : He 's hurting me .
I can 't open the door .
It 's blocked . Suzie ?
You 've got to push it from the inside .
SUZANNE : He 's hurting me .
Come on !
It 's no good .
SUZANNE : Get off me !
- ( WIND HOWLING LOUDER ) - ( SARAH GASPS )
Suzie ?
- Thank God . - ( CAT MEWLING )
No one 's gonna hurt you .
You 're safe here .
MIKE : Sarah ? Sarah !
( CAT SHRIEKING )
- ( WOMAN GASPS ) - ( CATS SHRIEKING )
MAN 1 : Clear the studio !
Get out !
MAN 2 : Quickly !
People are leaving the studio now .
- ( LIGHTS BURST ) - The lights are blowing all over the place .
MIKE : No , I 'm not going out .
- I 'm not going . Get the link back . - ( MICHAEL TALKING )
Get the link back . If somebody can get the link back ...
( INDISTINCT CHATTERING )
Lights ... I think we 're losing power .
MIKE : When you show me that my wife is safe , I 'll go .
We have got an emergency generator ...
- Whether or not we should bring it in , I don 't know . - MIKE : I 'm not going .
MICHAEL : The studio 's completely dark .
Just ... Just blackness now .
All the ... The lights have failed . The power 's gone off .
We 've got some ...
Some lights in the studio .
I don 't know ...
This camera 's ... I don 't know which one 's working . I mean ...
( CHUCKLING ) There are no cameramen .
I mean , it 's difficult to know
even if anybody 's still with us , but ...
- If they are , this is the scene in this ... - ( CATS MEWLING )
In this studio . This totally deserted studio .
Autocue 's working .
" Round and round the garden ...
" Like a teddy bear " ?
( CATS MEWLING )
GHOST : Didn 't believe those stories about Mother Seddons , did you ?
Fee fie foe fum ...
( CATS SHRIEKING )